Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials 1956-1964
ML31.W56
Boulanger, Nadia
Winslow, Harriet
95 items 1 container .25 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Little is known about Mrs. Cameron (Harriet) Winslow or how she became acquainted with the influential French composer, conductor, and teacher, Nadia Boulanger. This collection consists of photographs, concert programs, and clippings related to Boulanger's career that Mrs. Winslow received from 1956 to 1964. Most of the items are signed, dated and contain simple messages from Boulanger.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Blitzstein, Marc.; Boulanger, Lili, 1893-1918.; Boulanger, Nadia--Photographs.; Boulanger, Nadia.; Boulanger, Nadia.; Boulanger, Nadia. Harriet Winslow collection of Nadia Boulanger materials. 1956-1964.; Winslow, Harriet.
Organizations
Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau.
Subjects
Concert programs.; Music teachers--France.; Women conductors (Music)--France.
Titles
Winslow / Boulanger collection, 1956-1964
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift, Mrs. Cameron (Harriet) Winslow, July 26, 1977.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Little is known about Mrs. Cameron (Harriet) Winslow and her relationship with Nadia Boulanger. From 1956-1964, Winslow, then a resident of Washington, DC, received a variety of programs, clippings, and photographs from Boulanger, most signed and dated with simple messages, such as, "Pour Harriet de tout coeur." These items suggest that the two may have been friends, although reference sources on Boulanger bear no mention of her relationship with Winslow.
Scope and Content Note
The Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials spans the period 1956 to 1964 and consists of photographs, concert programs, and clippings related to the influential French composer, conductor, and teacher. All photographs are inscribed with notes or short greetings that identify the depicted individuals and places. Most portray Boulanger alone or with others, in her apartment, at the Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau, or while traveling. The majority of the programs are from the Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau and document performances by faculty members, students, and visiting ensembles. The remaining programs are from Boulanger's visits to the United States in 1958 and 1962 and from her visits to other countries between these dates. These special appearances, usually as conductor, performer, or teacher, are covered in greater detail in the clippings file. Also included is a record review by Marc Blitzstein about compositions by Lili Boulanger, sister of Nadia, who died at the age of twenty-four.
Organization of the Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials
The Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials is organized in three series:
Photographs, 1958-1964
Programs, 1956-1962
Clippings, 1957-1963
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006569273
Container List
- Photographs, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Nadia Boulanger, alone, 1958-1960, 4 photographs (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Nadia Boulanger, with others, 1960-1964, 7 photographs (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Organ in Nadia Boulanger's apartment, undated, 2 photographs (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Prince Rainier and Princess Grace of Monaco with children, 1960, 1 photograph (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Souzay, Gérard see Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau
- Programs, 1956-1962 (Box 1)
  - American Guild of Organists, Boston Chapter, 1962 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Association des concerts Lamoureux, 1959 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Bath Festival, 1960 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Composers' Showcase, 1962 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Dumbarton Oaks, 1958 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Festival Yehudi Menuhin, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Fondation Singer-Polignac, 1957, 1959 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Fontainebleau Schools (music and fine arts) 1959 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - King's Chapel, Boston, 1962 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Pine Manor Junior College, 1962 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Riyaseticumhur Senfoni Orkestrasi, 1958 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Tri-State Orchestral Composers Symposium, 1962 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Union Interalliée, 1958 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Clippings, 1957-1963, undated (Box 1)
  - 1957-1963, undated (Box-folder 1/3)